[
  {
    "question_text": "70 years old male patient with PFO, has DM, HTN, had lacunar stroke in posterior limb of internal capsule, CTA showed extracranial atherosclerosis, what is the treatment:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "closure PFO",
      "option_b": "Aspirin",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "patient with asymptomatic extracranial ICA 60% stenosis what is the best treatment:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "maximize medical therapy",
      "option_b": "carotid endarterectomy",
      "option_c": "carotid stenting.",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "patient with medial medullary syndrome which artery is affected:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "Posterior spinal Artery.",
      "option_b": "Anterior spinal Artery.",
      "option_c": "Basilar artery.",
      "option_d": "PICA",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "patient with acute stroke on dabigatrin for AF, the patient underwent for thrombectomy, the patient developed hemorrhage over MCA territory, what to give:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "Vit K.",
      "option_b": "",
      "option_c": "Idarocizumab.",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "patient with perimesencephalic SAH, angiogram done 2 times was normal, what to do next:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "send home",
      "option_b": "repeat digital subtraction angiogram",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "female patient presented with hx of flashing in the right eye, then she had right homonymous hemianopia, then left side weakness over 45min, the patient during her way she had headache. CT brain, CTA including DWI all normal, improved after s:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "hemiplegic migraine.",
      "option_b": "TIA",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "patient presented with acute stroke on warfarin CT showed ICH, INR=5, the patient received prothrombin complex, what to add for him:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "Vit K",
      "option_b": "FFP.",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "45 years old with hx of migraine 15 years ago, developed TIA, his father has stroke. MRI involving the anterior temporal lobe, what to do next:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "NOTCH 3",
      "option_b": "",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "female patient taking OCP, had CVT, thrombophilia work up was -ve, for how long to be on anticoagulation:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "life long.",
      "option_b": "3-6 months",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "patient over 1 day he has symptoms of vertigo & ataxia, CT shown: there was left cerebellar hypodensity, midline shift & crowding of the posterior fossa, what to do next:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "start Aspirin.",
      "option_b": "Give tPA",
      "option_c": "consult neurosurgery",
      "option_d": "admit ICU & monitor ICP",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2019",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Male patient present with lacinating pain last for seconds and MRI done showed SCA compress over trigeminal nerve RX?:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "Decompressive surgery",
      "option_b": "carbamazepine",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "scenario about child have ?ADHD and (cafe au late ash laf flickers\u2026.) dx?",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "",
      "option_b": "",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "1",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Case scenario of a patient who came with left PICA? territory infarction (attached CT brain) asked about what\u2019s next?",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "Neurosurgery consultation",
      "option_b": "Dual anti-platelet",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "B",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Cadasil scenario of pt tried stroke dementia migraine asked about how to dx??",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "(assuming it represents this combined approach) is thus correct. Other options, such as CT brain, skin biopsy alone, CSF analysis, or angiography, are either less sensitive or nonspecific and therefore incorrect.",
      "option_b": "",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Picture of MRA Time of float (floating thrombus) and asking what you want to do next ..?? STENOSIS (\u0627\u0644\u0635\u0648\u0631\u0629 \u0627\u0644\u0645\u0648\u062c\u0648\u062f\u0629 \u0641\u064a \u0627\u0644\u0627\u062e\u062a\u0628\u0627\u0631 \u0645\u0643\u0627\u0646 \u0641\u064a\u0647\u0627 \u0648\u0645\u0643\u0627\u0646\u0627\u062a \u0648\u0627\u0636\u062d\u0647 \u0628\u0633 \u0647\u0630\u064a \u0627\u0644\u0635\u0648\u0631\u0629 \u0644\u0644\u062a\u0642\u0631\u064a\u0628)",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "heparin infusion",
      "option_b": "start hydrocortisone",
      "option_c": "?surgery",
      "option_d": "dual or single anti platet",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Elderly had embolic stroke, what to do next:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "is correct because initiating anticoagulation directly addresses the thromboembolic source, significantly reducing the risk of recurrent strokes. Options that suggest antiplatelet therapy alone or no treatment are inadequate in preventing further embolic events, as antiplatelets do not provide sufficient protection in cardioembolic stroke.",
      "option_b": "",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Cadasil scenario of pt tried stroke dementia migraine what to giv pat foe prophlaxis ??",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "smoking cessation",
      "option_b": "anti-goagulant (warfarin)",
      "option_c": "!ASA",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Same above Q what Rx:",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "Anticoaglation",
      "option_b": "",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Scenario about old age man around 80 y.o k/c of DM, HTN, stroke 2 months back Came with stroke in windo .. (Ct attached showed good aspect and old cortical insult) what TO DO NEXT ?",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "IV tpA",
      "option_b": "IV tpA followed by thrombectomy",
      "option_c": "",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "C",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  },
  {
    "question_text": "Why tpa contraindicated in previous Q",
    "options": {
      "option_a": "stroke less than 3mo (Relative contraindication)",
      "option_b": "Or The presence of exclusion criteria",
      "option_c": "pt can be benefit of thrombectomy",
      "option_d": "",
      "option_e": ""
    },
    "correct_answer": "A",
    "explanation": "",
    "subspecialty": "vascular_neurology",
    "exam_year": "2021",
    "exam_type": "Promotion"
  }
]